VENKAT RAMSHESH (LinkedIn)

WORK HISTORY

Field Engineer, 05/2022 - present United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS)

- Installation and support for laptops, workstations, printers, and AV equipment of USCIS staff, students, classroom, and offices ensuring minimal downtime
- Troubleshooting computer, printers, scanners, and network issues
- Regular system software updates, hardware fixes, imaging of computers, maintenance of system servers and switches, UPS, VPN/remote worker support
- Addressing of tickets, customer issues in a timely manner and inventory management, PowerShell for active directory reports. CompTIA A+ certified
- AWS Community Builder, Certified in AWS Solutions Architect Associate and Certified Cloud Practitioner. AWS Serverless learning badge. Written several blogs and implemented projects for:

Networking: VPC, Subnets, NAT, IGW, Egress gateway, Workspaces, VLANS, routers, switches, wireless access points, TOR router

Highly available and scalable architecture: Conference raffle webpage using CloudFormation, ALB and autoscaling.

Instances: Blog page on EC2 instance (http://44.207.232.191:8000/), RDS instances for database, Jump box

Serverless/Event Driven: API's, Lambda function, Dynamo DB tables,

SNS, SQS, SAM, Transcribing, chat app

Storage: S3 for static website (https://vramsheshpersonalblog.com), EFS, EBS and file transfer family

Automation: CI/CD, Jenkins, Ansible, Elastic beanstalk for raffle webpage, Docker for HTTP server, CloudFormation templates, Python boto3 for creating S3 buckets, Systems Manager

Databases: SQL and NoSQL databases

Security/Delivery: Encryption, SSL certificates for website, Presigned URL, site-site and client VPN, CDN, Secrets Manager, IAM,

Organizations, Cognito, penetration testing

Migration/upkeep: Server and database migration

Query: Athena

• Learnt Python, HTML/CSS (front-end), and Flask (back-end) programming during personal time. (Code for few projects: https://github.com/kris1878/pythonprojects) Implemented projects:

HTML/CSS: Personal website (https://vramsheshpersonalblog.com)

Serverless: s3 photos, video transcribing

Flask/API: Personal blog, Café shops, Calorie tracker, Stock news, Spotify songs list, URL shortener, serverless chat app

Games: Pong, snake, turtle race, quizzlet

Security: SSL certificate tracker, packet sniffer, password generator

Lifestyle: Pomodoro, rain alert, birthday wisher

Graphing: Stock graphing project using matplotlib, web scraping Used libraries like Flask, Requests, Pandas, Matplotlib, Plotly, NumPy, boto3, beautiful soup and Turtle for these projects.

• Preparing for the AWS Professional certification, CCNA, and currently dabbling in JS and Linux.

Field Engineer II, 11/2020 - 05/2021 Cytek Biosciences

- Installation and support for **Aurora flow cytometer** in Philly/NJ area in a timely manner
- Regular system preventative and update visits
- Identified major system issues that could arise and provided solutions for these problems.
- Adjusting parts stock, generating install and PM reports
- Updating manuals, technical documentation







PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated, collaborative biomedical engineer skilled in IT, cloud, programming, and microscopy. Effective IT field engineer offering excellent skills in installation, training, maintenance, and testing of systems. Forward-thinking professional offering years of experience working in fast-paced environments. Known for reliability and knowledge. Organized and dependable candidate successful at managing multiple priorities with a positive attitude.

CERTIFICATIONS & MEMBERSHIPS

 AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, September 2022 CVBPEGQCRJE4Q1S0



 AWS cloud practitioner, June 2022 KCZ7CJ8JFEB4Q0KH



• AWS Community Builder, March 2023



 AWS Serverless learning plan badge, March 2023



 CompTIA A+, March 2023 COMP001022210326



Field Engineer II, 04/2020 - 11/2020 Cytiva

- Installation and support for OMX super resolution microscopes (OMX V3, V4, SR, SR plus and FLEX models) in North America, Asia, and Europe in a timely manner
- Troubleshooting and fixing system issues on-site and remotely
- Minimizing average downtimes ~1 week
- Yearly preventive maintenance (PM) and hardware/software updates
- Updating manuals, technical documentation
- Adjusting parts stock, generating install and PM reports, quotations

Field Engineer I, 01/2015 - 03/2020 GE Healthcare Lifesciences

- Installation and support for **GE OMX super resolution** (OMX V3, V4, SR and SR plus models) and Delta Vision microscopes in North America, Asia and Europe
- Trained users on image analysis software
- Troubleshooting and fixing system issues on-site and remotely
- Yearly PM and hardware/software updates
- Customer support and training of end users both remotely and on site, updating manuals.
- Hired and supervised subcontractors to improve production and meet critical deadlines.
- Interacted effectively with site engineering team and field staff to coordinate work that complied with design and installation documents.

Research Instructor/Facility Manager, 07/2011 - 12/2014 Medical University of South Carolina

- Provide bioengineering and managerial support for the successful day to day working of the Advanced Imaging Core which include eight confocal, multiphoton & fluorescence microscopes and image processing workstations.
- Instruct users on microscopy/imaging usage and projects, consult on projects involving use of light microscopy techniques within and outside the university.
- Consulted users on image analysis and processing.
- Organizer and instructor for the 2014 Fifth and 2012 Fourth Charleston Light Microscopy Workshop for the Biosciences
- Assisted in successful NIH grant application as part of Cell and Molecular Imaging resource.
- Expanded the core instrumentation from two to eight microscopes during my tenure.
- Led facility management staff and consultants in producing business plan that focused on facility operations.

Bioengineer/Facility Manager, 12/2007 - 06/2011 Medical University of South Carolina

- Provide bioengineering and managerial support for the successful day to day working of the center for cell death, injury, and regeneration (CCDIR) and cell and molecular imaging resources.
- Organized and instructed for the 2010 Third and 2008 Second Charleston Light Microscopy Workshop for the Biosciences
- Assisted in successful NCI and NIH grant application from Hollings Cancer Center as part of Cell and Molecular Imaging resource.
- Evaluated facility operations and personnel for safety and health regulations compliance

- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) XCZBAVAEH675
- Cisco Certified Network Associate, May 2000 (Working on recertification)

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Python, Matlab, C, Image J, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Node JS

EDUCATION

Ph.D., Biomedical Engineering, 2008 University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill

M.S, Biomedical Engineering, 2002 University of North Carolina - **Chapel Hill**

B.E, Instrumentation Engineering, 1999 Mumbai University/University of Mumbai

PROFFESIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Reviewer for Journal of Biomedical Optics, Methods and Microscopy & Microanalysis
- Intravital Imaging Symposium at NIH, Bethesda, May 2011
- 2009 Workshop on FRET Microscopy, University of Virginia, Charlottesville
- Analytical and Quantitative Light Microscopy Course 2006, Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole, Massachusetts

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Member of UNC squash team
- Recreational salsa dancer and tennis player

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Ramshesh VK, Lemasters JJ. Pinhole shifting lifetime imaging microscopy (PSLIM). Journal of Biomedical Optics, 13 (6):064001, Nov-Dec 2008

Ramshesh VK, Knisley SB. Use of light absorbers to alter optical interrogation with epi-illumination and transillumination in 3-d cardiac models. Journal of Biomedical Optics 2006; 11

Ramshesh VK, Knisley SB. Spatial localization of cardiac optical mapping with multiphoton excitation. Journal of Biomedical Optics 2003; 8:253-259